Name Adam Lee

Telephone 07913041037

E-mail alee8648@gmail.com

**Profile** 

Constructive content marketer with the drive to develop a broad array of abilities including copywriting, statistical analysis, and digital skills. A natural learner and inquisitive researcher with a First Class Modern Languages degree from Durham University.

## Education

# University of Durham

# First Class BA(Hons) Modern Languages and Cultures (Spanish & Italian)

Oct 2009 - Jun 2013

- Particularly impressive results (80%+) in well-researched and professionally written critical analysis essays including creatively inclined work such as academic film reviews and literary translations
- Strong analytical skills developed on linguistic, cultural, and intercultural levels through study of literature, linguistics, history, art, and cinema
- Recommended for Post-graduate study in Visual Arts, Film, or Literature
- Structured, methodical approach to tasks and deadline management
- Found and ran a Book Club Society, heading the group as discussion leader

# Sleaford Joint Sixth Form

'A' Level, 'AS' Level

Sep 2007 - Jul 2009

'A' grade achieved in Spanish, French, English Language and Maths at 'AS' and 'A'
Level, 'A' grade achieved in Critical Thinking at 'AS' Level (prior to introduction of A\*
grades)

# **Employment**

## **BANG+STRIKE**

## Marketing and Social Media Assistant

(Online retailer of men's underwear)

Aug 2014 - Feb 2015

- Responsible for content on the site's numerous social channels, including Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Pinterest, Tumblr, and Google+, and co-ordinating with the Marketing Manager and Creative Director to deliver the marketing strategy evenly across all platforms
- Principal blog-writer, responsible for creation of interesting, creative, and SEO-friendly
  content on WordPress. Wrote up both my own ideas and those sourced from creative
  meetings, and co-ordinated them with graphic designer to create appealing blogs
- PR responsibilities including communicating with models and other public figures to create Q&A posts, and outreach to relevant sites to feature our blogs
- Monitored Google Analytics on a weekly basis for feedback on blog popularity, inbound links, and social media coverage. Also attended Google Analytics training day allowing the company to access new insights
- Researched and monitored competitors and the market, optimising social media and blogs to keep up with advances where possible

#### Freelance work

# Copywriter, Blogger, and Social Media Consultant

Sep 2014 - Present

- Took on a large project for Patchworks.co.uk (digital agency) writing enticing and descriptive landing pages for prospective clients, creating hundreds of iterations of a similar product page for optimal SEO purposes
- Began a blog series for Universityofwhatever.co.uk (online loungewear retailer) and simple social media strategy to create an online presence for the budding brand
- Optimised Amazon listings for University of Whatever for traffic, exposure, and conversion with convincing copy and measured experimentation
- Compiled and wrote justified and cogent finance applications, including business proposals, for University of Whatever, helping to secure funding for a new print studio
- Edited and rewrote customer communication for Hampton Dean chartered financial advisors according to their specification, making a complex subject intelligible for clients

# Media Measurement (Social media analytics)

May - Jul 2014

# **Research Analyst Intern**

- Quickly learnt to use Salesforce's Radian6 social media monitoring tool, immediately assisting on two team projects to produce reports for client Reckitt Benckiser within my first week
- Analysed and critiqued effectiveness of social media campaigns for FMCG brands, gaining insight on customer/market usage of social platforms, and discovering opportunities for brand engagement for clients
- Wrote a blog post based on my own findings using the Radian6 social monitoring tool
- Planned and produced individual written projects to deadlines, such as well-researched industry blogs for the company site and snapshot reports for clients such as Unilever
- Employed language and cultural skills in order to analyse data from global markets in Spanish, Italian, and French
- Compiled a list of recommendations for the improvement of the Radian6 software, including small changes that would save its users countless man-hours

## **UOW Limited**

(Online clothing startup)

Aug 2013 - May 2014

# **Amazon Marketing Specialist**

- Improving, optimising, and experimenting on the site's existing Amazon listings, including breakthroughs that doubled the brand's traffic and allowed the business to develop
- Regularly analysed sales, page views and conversion rates through weekly reports and the creation of a database, allowing the company to highlight problematic and successful listings
- Responsible for all copywriting the website, product descriptions, brand message and communications with translators and web developers
- Exposed to broad range of business activities, here is where I developed my interest in copywriting, marketing, and analysis

# Year Abroad 7 months in Spain, 4 months in Italy 2011-2012

# Enforex (Spain)

Jul - Aug 2011

# University of Granada (Spain)

Sep 2011 - Feb 2012

IIS Rolando da Piazzola (Italy) Apr - Jun 2012

Europass (Italy)

Aug - Sep 2012

# English camp language teacher

 Communication and teamwork skills challenged by co-ordinating large groups of teenagers with other tutors unsupervised by seniors.

# Erasmus programme

 Significant time spent living abroad - studying in a different language and culture and socialising with other students from across the world

#### English language assistant (Secondary school in Italy)

• Clear communication and creativity essential for engaging teenagers in language activities, both planned personally and by others.

### Intensive advanced Italian language course

• Cultural awareness and linguistic skills expanded whilst living and studying in Florence

# Skills & Competencies

Languages English (native), Spanish (fluent), Italian (fluent), French (good)

## Digital

- Highly proficient in use of social media platforms Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest,
   Tumblr, Google+, YouTube, and social media management systems Hootsuite and Buffer. Well accustomed to use of WordPress for blogs.
- Experience and training in use of Google analytics, and familiarity with Google AdWords. Experienced in use of Radian6 social media analytics.
- · Proficient use of MS Office
- Experienced in use of Magento and Amazon Seller Central.
- Self-taught beginner level understanding of HTML (including Bootstrap), CSS, and JavaScript (including jQuery).
- Self-confessed geek I enjoy teaching myself programming languages, am always keen to pick up new digital skills, and regularly do my own research on multiple aspects of writing!